Daniel Castellanos

Senior Software Developer

Profile

Software Engineer with eight years of experience creating and developing mobile apps, PWA, WebApps, and APIS, five years of working using a JavaScript frameworks like Angular, ReactJs, VueJS, StencilJs, React Native, and Ionic. Experience with relational and non-relational such as Oracle, SQL Server, MySQL, and MongoDB. Strong experience implementing Agile methodologies such as Scrum and Kanban: in additional worked in different industries Insures, Banking, only MarketPlaces and IT services.

Employment History

Senior Software Developer at Mercado Libre, Bogota

November 2022 — Present

I am part of the Product Page Team which is in charge of the user experience. I'm responsible for the design and improvement of the product and item features of our company's website

- React UI libs development.
- Development of micro frontends.
- Frontend design focused on security, scalability, reuse, web performance, SEO and accessibility.
- Frontend development based on Node + React + Express.
- Development of middleware for frontends in nodes.

.

Senior Front-End Developer at Ressolve (Freelance), Bogotá

November 2020 — January 2024

I am part of the Front-End team which is in charge of the user experience, create new features in the platform and solve issues:

- Developed a platform using in Vue.Js with primary framework, Vuetify with UI library, and Vuex to management the state..
- Created a audio player with a karaoke feature created in Vue.Js and wavesurfer.js.
- Migrate platform developed in Vue.JS to Angular
- Optimized the front-end user interface for improved UX/UI, resulting in a X% increase in user engagement

Senior Software Developer at Perficient, Medellin

December 2018 — October 2022

Software development for the Insurance, regional IT services and Health Care industry

- Designed and developed requirements in AngularJs.
- Created a native application with Angular, cordova and NgRx.
- Designed and developed a system using RxJs to manage the state of the application using Angular 12 of framework..
- · Created unit test using Jest and Karma

Details

Bogotá Colombia

+573203161547

castellanosarangod@gmail.com

Links

linkedin GitHub

Skills

Linux

Git

HTML & CSS

HTML5

CSS3

JavaScript

TypeScript

Angular

React.is

Vuejs

Stencil.js

ionic.js

RxJs

Redux

NgRx

Node.js

Express

Nest.js

Bootstrap

Material Designe

sass

less

jest

Jasmine

PlayWrite

- Created a WebApp with React and Material-UI with UI system.
- Created a unit testing using React Testing library and Jest.

Sofware Developer at Asesoftware, Bogota D.C

July 2018 — November 2018

Software developer in focus the areas of Finance and banking with participation in projects:

- Maintenance a banck software applications made in languages like Scala in the Back-End, and JavaScript in Front-End.
- Leader of front-end development focused on building software for the optimization of legal demand processes in the banking sector. this sofwate was created in technologies such as JavaScript, TypeScript, Angular 6, Angular Material, MomentJs, Bootstrap, Sass.

System Analyst Developer at BNP Paribas Cardif, Bogota D.C

April 2017 — June 2018

Solutions analyst for the satellite and regional applications of the the company, these applications were made in Java, Visual Basic, C#, using frameworks like .Net, Jsf, PrimeFaces, Spring, and Hibernate.

- Creation and implementation of an application that will be a success in the migration of an old system made in Visual Basic to Java.
- ETL Creation using technologies such as Integration Services.
- Analyst in charge of supporting the different reports of the company and the creation of new reports depending on the request of the user, the reports were made with: Reporting Services (SSRS), Crystal Report, and Web Report.

Analyst Semi Senior at EBS LTDA, Bogota D.C

December 2014 — March 2017

Software developer in Java, C#, and Visual Basic. Implementing Frameworks or libraries like Hibernate, Ibatis, Spring, Struts, JSP, JSF, Prime Faces, and JQuery, and implementing database engines like Oracle and SQL-Server.

Support and maintenance of applications developed in JAVA,
Visual Basic, and C#. Active participation in different projects and clients

Education

Computer Engineering, Universidad Santo Tomás de Colombia, Bogota D.C

January 2018 — Present

Courses

Cloud Foundations, AWS Academy

August 2021 — December 2022

NewRelic

DataDog

SQL

Docker

Python

Java

MongoDB

Oracle

SQL Server

MySQL

Languages

English

Spanish; Castilian